All right, so on
my first channel, Film
Booth, my viewers didn't
need much depth. I
could skip a lot
of the step -by
-step instructions and I
could still get amazing
results. But when I
repositioned my channel to
help business owners grow
through YouTube, that changed
because suddenly surface level
content didn't really work
as well for them.
They wanted clarity, they
wanted more details, they
wanted systems, but I
couldn't just dump a
wall of information on
them because that will
kill results too. So
I had to figure
out how to give
people the structure and
proof they needed without
losing the whole new,
easy, and inspiring feeling
that makes content perform.
And that is where
the logic brick comes
in. So in this
video, I'm going to
show you how to
build logic bricks that
feel clear, not overwhelming,
build trust and credibility,
and help your viewers
take action fast, as
well as make your
content feel more valuable.
All right, so let's
start with what makes
an amazing logic brick.
So the good job
of a logic brick
is this. On this
table, you can see
a ton of sticky
notes, and on each
one is written a
different topic that I
can position as something
that you need to
build. To get more
sales views and leads.
So you've got hooks,
editing, watch time, click
through, calls to action,
niches, titles. You get
the idea. Now imagine
trying to explain all
that in a single
video. It would be
absolutely chaos. It would
be overloaded. No one
will remember a thing,
and no one would
take any action. And
that's the problem most
people run into with
their videos. Their videos
are packed with tips,
but none of it
sticks. So our goal
for every video is
to do this, and
to work out only
the things that matter
to achieve the results
we promised in the
setup from the title.
And the thing that
makes this hard is,
in your head, you're
going to think you
always need to include
100 % of the
things needed to get
the viewer result from
your content. But what
I need you to
do is to become
the person who only
gives the viewer 20
% of the things
they need, but the
most important 20%, that
if the viewer actions
them, will get them
the biggest result. When
you do that, they're
going to be like,
that was easy, this
person's a genius, I'm
coming back, and they're
going to feel like
your information's new, easy,
and inspiring. So now
you understand what the
logic brick is, and
why most creators mess
it up, let me
show you how to
actually build one. Because
if we want to
make our content feel
simple and powerful without
overwhelming the viewer, we
need to use the
right tools for the
job again. And after
writing thousands of scripts
and testing everything, I've
narrowed it down to
only really three tools.
The first is frameworks,
where you simplify big
ideas. The second is
proof. Where you build
trust and credibility. And
the third is just
using really simple checklists
and on -screen steps
to kind of anchor
attention, to keep viewers
driving through the video,
feeling motivated. Now we're
going to go through
each one of them
one by one, and
then I'm going to
show you examples of
how to use them
in your own content.
So let's start with
the first, frameworks. So
think of a framework
as a container for
your viewer's brain, and
instead of dumping 12
sticky notes on them,
you group them into
just three clean blocks
that they can actually
remember and act on.
By the way, three
is an example, not
a rule. But if
I'm honest, most of
the time, I'm always
thinking in threes because
anything more can become
too overwhelming. So here's
an example of a
framework in action. So
the entrepreneurial sweet spot
is the convergence of
three key things. The
first one is that
you are doing something
that you are passionate
about. So you have
to love what you
do. The next one
is that you are
delivering outcomes. You're delivering
value for customers. And
the third one is
that you're getting paid
to do the work.
So the takeaway here
is that it is
not about going to
the extremes. If I
were to go to
the extreme of my
passion, I might find
snowboarding, but I'm not
delivering outcomes for others,
and no one's willing
to pay me to
do it. If I
was to look at
who would pay me
the most, it might
be corporate clients, but
those are not my
favourite types of clients.
I love working with
entrepreneurs. If I was
to focus on delivering
outcomes at the expense
of everything else, I
might go into government,
or I might go
into academia, right? Where
I'm focusing on out
on these kinds of
outcomes. And it might
be at the expense
of my passion, but
I might not be.
or how much I
could be paid. So
what we're looking for
is to triangulate and
to actually figure out
what's here in the
middle. Two out of
three doesn't cut it.
If you love what
you do and you're
getting paid well but
you're not delivering outcomes,
it starts to feel
unethical. If you are
delivering outcomes for others,
you're getting paid well
but you're not passionate,
it feels unfulfilling. If
you are passionate, you're
delivering outcomes for others
but you're not being
paid very well, it
feels unrewarding. So essentially
you must get yourself
to these three or
else you will potentially
burn out. My personal
belief is that burnout
is when you don't
have all three of
these. So frameworks are
the fastest way to
make your instructional content
feel simple, structured and
memorable, especially when you're
trying to explain something
that normally feels overwhelming.
And there's different types
of frameworks but there's
three that I use
a lot and I
recommend. The first one
you see on YouTube
all of the time
and it's as simple
as listing the steps
a viewer needs to
take to get a
result. Now, step -by
-step instructions are great
when you're teaching something
that happens in a
specific order, like a
process or a journey.
And here's an example
of that in action.
Which brings us on
to step three. So
have you ever been
invited to someone's house
and walked in and
gone, oh my gosh,
this person lives in
an absolute pigsty, what
a tip. And you
kind of want to
leave, right? Cause you're
worried there's a rat
infestation. Well, your videos
have the same effect
if your background is
a complete mess. So
when it comes to
your backdrop, all we
really need to do
is something that firstly,
doesn't give that messy,
disgusting home feeling, but
also secondly, doesn't distract
people. So basically each
step just builds on
the last and it
promises a finish line,
which helps the viewer
feels like they're making
progress. Now people often
name their steps or
make them sound unique
by saying things like,
here's my three -step
system or here's my
five -day launch plan.
So that's the first
type. The next type
of framework is an
acronym. So BENZ, which
I taught you in
the title video, means
big, easy, safe, and
new. And it's very
easy to remember because
viewers remember the name
and then they remember
what each letter represents
so long as it's
catchy. And then the
final type that's very
powerful is something I
use a lot called
visual shape frameworks. Now
I like these because
sometimes the fastest way
to explain an idea
is just to simplify
it down to a
shape, which you can
draw. And you're going
to see a lot
of the biggest educators
on YouTube use these.
Now there are many
ways you can do
this, but there's five
that I use a
lot. So firstly, arrows.
You can use this
if your idea happens
in a sequence. So
arrows are perfect when
you're explaining a process
or a journey or
something when one step
naturally leads onto the
next. So think step
one, step two, step
three. Each step just
builds on the last.
So you can see,
right, how easy that
is to understand as
an overview of a
process when it's broken
up into just a
few words. Now this
works because us humans
love a clear start
and finish. It feels
satisfying and it gives
you a roadmap. So
you want to use
it when you're teaching
a system that works
in a strict order.
You want to show
progress of transformation over
time, or you want
viewers to kick off
each step as they
go. Then we have
pyramids or triangles. So
I use triangles all
of the time to
point out the core
ingredients to success. Remember
this one, new, easy,
and expiring? Doesn't that
just make it sound
so much less overwhelming
seeing you only really
need these three things
and that's why they
work so well because
they help your viewer
instantly grasp that these
three things work together
and that each one
is essential. So I'd
recommend using this when
you want to show
the three most important
things and the most
important components of a
result. You want to
visually emphasize that all
three matter equally and
you want your viewers
to remember a principle,
not a process. And
this is fantastic for
mindset shifts, positioning frameworks,
or big takeaways that
just don't need a
sequence. And then the
next type is cycles.
So our entire fail
as fast as you
can framework is one
of these. So cycles
are ideal when the
process you're teaching just
loops over. They work
because viewers understand, ah,
they're never done. It
just repeats. And you
improve as you repeat.
So you want to
use this if you're
teaching a system that
gets better with time.
You want to help
viewers embrace iteration. You
want to avoid making
the learning feel one
and done or when
your steps repeat. And
then we have Venn
diagrams. So like this.
This is where you
say you need three
things and when they
all overlap, that's when
you create something powerful.
So also when you
isolate what's essential. So
you want to use
these when you're blending
skills and topics or
strategies, or you want
to show where the
real magic happens, or
you want to teach
viewers how different things
connect. And then we
have funnels. Funnels are
perfect when your viewer
needs to start broad,
then gradually fill a
focus down to something
specific, like an action
or a product or
a decision. So you've
probably seen these used
a lot in the
marketing space to show
how cold buyers are
top of funnel, and
then the ones down
the bottom are hotter.
Now these things work
because they show progressive
focus from a lot
of noise to one
clear step. And you
want to use this
when you're teaching how
to turn your attention
into action, or you
want to show how
value increases, through each
stage, or you want
to simplify a marketing
or customer journey. So
each of these shapes
I've showed you reduces
cognitive load, but how
do you come up
with frameworks? Because when
you do this, your
brain's going to feel
totally overwhelmed with options.
So here's the process
I'd recommend to get
unstuck. Firstly, just write
down every point you
could possibly make, just
dump everything, lessons, tools,
steps, mistakes, don't hold
back. This is your
mess phase. You'll probably
have way more things
than you can use,
and that's okay. And
if that takes you
hours to do, don't
worry. Once you've got
clarity, everything else speeds
up. And then the
second step is you
want to ask, what's
the result I'm trying
to help the viewer
get? Now this question
narrows your focus. It
stops you from teaching
everything and helps you
prioritize only what's essential
to achieve the promise
from your title and
your thumbnail and your
intro. Then in the
next step, you circle
the three most important
parts that will get
them that result. So
ask, if my viewer
could only do three
things to get that
result, which three would
I give them? What
you're looking for here
is the vital 20
% that creates the
biggest success. And then
what you do is
you pick the framework.
So if they happen
in an order, use
arrow. Do they stack
and support each other?
Use a pyramid. Do
they overlap? Use a
Venn diagram. Do they
form a loop? Use
a cycle. Do they
compare? Use a triangle
or funnel. Do they
share a first letter?
Use an acronym. And
then just name your
framework. You don't have
to do this, but
it will make your
information feel new so
that people don't write
it off as I've
heard this before. And
then we just test
it. So use it
in a video. If
viewers comment things like,
oh, I had a
light bulb moment. Oh,
this is so good.
It's so easy to
understand. Or if your
clients repeat it back
to you, you're onto
something, you can keep
repeating it. You can
own that framework and
then you can become
known for it. Now
again, like everything, this
takes a huge amount
of practice. You're not
gonna be good at
this straight away. All
right, so next we're
gonna look at how
to add proof to
your point so that
people actually believe what
you're saying. Right, so
at this point, after
your framework, the viewer
is gonna be going,
ah, this makes sense,
but has it actually
worked for anyone? And
if you don't answer
that with something visual
specific or undeniable, you're
gonna lose some trust.
So the next important
part of the logic
brick is to always
include some proof that
your framework works. So
here's a quick example
of that. I'm gonna
show you the new
way to build out
your channel strategy step
by step so that
it can grow faster.
Like all of the
examples I've worked on
screen and one day
become capable of generating
a million dollars. So
whenever you're introducing something
new, you always wanna
think about that cold
viewer who's never heard
of you before and
doesn't trust you, doesn't
even like you. And
you wanna drop in
proof that following the
information is gonna work
for them with a
proof line. And then
ideally you show the
proof. Now there's four
types of proof that
I use. First with
personal results, where I
just show a screenshot
of my own analytics.
The next is client
wins, where I show
screenshots of their analytics
or discord messages. Then
there's before and afters.
So I just show
a visual proof of
result. And then there's
live examples. So I
might play a clip
from a video where
someone's actually saying this
worked for me. Now,
one really important thing
you need to get
into the habit of
doing is, you see
this endless scroll? This
is hundreds of times,
this is hundreds of
screenshots of proof that
I have helped people
win. And that is
going to be critical
for your videos and
your marketing. So screenshot
anything you see that
is positive, emails, comments,
graphs, messages. Don't worry
about sharing it. Blur
everyone's name so we
don't have to ask
for permission or just
email them and say,
hey, can I use
this just to make
sure that they're okay
with that. But you
need a bank of
these. And if you
ever see one, drop
everything you are doing,
screenshot and go back
to it. It's the
only time I ever
lose focus. I'm not
gonna focus on something
because they're so powerful
for our videos. But
also don't be afraid
to use the same
screenshots over and over
again. Like it's not
pulling the wall over
people's eyes. It's just
saying here, this works.
So now your viewers
believe the idea, you
need to help them
implement it. And that's
where our third way
to level up the
logic that comes in.
And it can be
as simple as doing
this. So you see
on screen, I'm just
listing the points I'm
making in the video.
So these checklists, they
make long sections feel
structured. They reduce cognitive
load. This way the
viewer always knows where
they are in your
process, what matters most
and how to take
action after the video.
The next very simple
thing I do to
help remove overwhelm and
to make viewers feel
like they're progressing has
the same kind of
effect as when you're
reading a book, but
kind of wondering, should
you put it down
now or at the
end of the chapter?
And I do that
by just showing the
step on screen. So
when a new one
starts, this pops up
and it's like, oh,
look, I've made some
progress. It's like a
visual transition too. So
really the logic brick
is just about making
sure your instructions feel
easy to follow and
keep progressing whilst not
overwhelming people, but also
provide proof that it
works so they actually
wanna listen. But what
happens at the end
of a logic brick?
We need to bring
back our trusty little
friend, Mr. Transition to
connect the end of
the logic brick to
the next point. And
just remember a good
transition does two things.
It signals a shift
forward in the video
so viewers feel like
they're progressing and it
states what's coming will
solve one of the
three problems you think
your buyers care about
the most. So for
example, okay, so let's
move on to the
second step, which is
the part that helped
me. Let me double
my sales. So now
you have different tools
to create emotion, different
tools to structure your
info. Next, I'm gonna
show you how to
end the video to
create a bin session
that is critical for
this entire system to
work.